Guide to the John Jacob Wolfe Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Jacob Wolfe papers
1939-1970
MS 1682
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The papers consist of correspondence and printed material collected by John and Esther Wolfe during their wartime stay in Bikaner, India, in the early 1940s.
Wolfe, John Jacob, 1903 or 1904-1990
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Esther Wolfe, 1994.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
John Jacob Wolfe received degrees from the Royal Dental Hospital (London University) in 1923, from Columbia University in 1925, and from Yale Medical School in 1933. He was an instructor at the School of Dentistry, New York University, from 1927-1928; chief of the dental clinic at Peiping Union Medical School from 1932-1935; and then entered private practice.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence and printed material collected by John and Esther Wolfe during their wartime stay in Bikaner, India, in the early 1940s.
Bīkāner (India); Bikaner (Princely State); Wolfe, John Jacob, 1903 or 1904-1990
- Original accession
  - Correspondence, 1941-1950, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Holiday greetings, 1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Program for the Golden Jubilee celebrations of The Maharajah of Bikaner (1887-1937), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Protocol instructions, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Speech of The Maharajah of Bikaner to troops, 1940 November (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, programs, menus, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proclamation on the departure of The Maharajah of Bikaner for active service, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Detailed Instructions Relating to the Visit to Bikaner of Their Excellencies The Viceroy and The Marchioness of Linlithgow", 1942 February (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Military exercises: printed description of, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)